Craig Stevenson

Game and Interactive Software Designer

Baltimore, MD - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Craig-Stevenson/f761a3b2e05bd30a

A digital chef bringing six years experience from game design, eLearning and instructional design. My curiosity encourages me to seek out new and exciting challenges that help keep my portfolio fresh.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Game Designer, Co-Founder

PixelBot Games, LLC - Baltimore, MD - December 2013 to Present

Co-founded indie startup to learn the commercial game development and self-publishing process.

- Released our first title, CANARI to Itch.io game delivery platform on PC/MAC.
- · Developed my public relations skills by demoing builds at area game events.
- Crafted a social media presence aimed at increasing visibility and web presence.

Game Designer

MedStar SiTEL - Washington, DC - December 2010 to Present

Design 2D/3D online educational training and simulation games using the Unity game engine.

• Responsible for strategy, planning, and design of game mechanics and assessments of complex topics in the healthcare

field.

- Managed a team of 10 programmers and artists along with a project producer.
- Prototype game features, create design documents, write testing plans and usability labs.
- Develop training solutions using Unity3D, Unreal4, Microsoft Visual Studio 2010 Pro, XML, and Microsoft Office.
- Deployed software to the web (HTML5), mobile (iOS/Android), PC/MAC, and virtual reality platforms (GearVR, Oculus,

SteamVR).

Learning Designer/Developer

Allegis Group, Inc - Hanover, MD - June 2010 to December 2010

Creating internal training websites and interactive animations for a variety of clients in the IT, medical, and construction

industries.

- Interpreting storyboards from Instructional Designers and Subject Matter Experts
- Video editing from raw footage using green screen keying and motion graphics in Adobe After Effects CS5.
- Testing functionality.
- Developing using XHTML/CSS and SSI, Adobe Flash CS4, Actionscript 3, Composica, SCORM compliant.

Instructional Designer

CONNECTIONS ACADEMY - Fells Point, MD - May 2005 to June 2007

Creating interactive training modules that would support the curriculum designed by teachers and administrators.

• Computer graphics, audio, animation, and testing assessments using Adobe Captivate, Flash, Photoshop, and Adobe

Soundbooth

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Technical or Professional Studies

University of Baltimore 2006

SKILLS

FLASH (5 years), ACTIONSCRIPT (3 years), ARTICULATE (2 years), AUTODESK MAYA (2 years), Unity (6 years), C# (2 years), Game Design (6 years), Virtual Reality (1 year), Unreal (3 years)

LINKS

http://www.mysorethumbs.com

http://www.pixelbotgames.com

AWARDS

Best In Show - Runner Up

February 2017

Presented conference talk on Serious Games in Healthcare field. Received best in show award - runner up for large corporation at International Meeting of Simulation in Healthcare conference for Trauma Yellow. Trauma Yellow is a game that puts the player in the role of team leader during a series of emergencies.

Best Mobile Application - Virtual Zoll Defibrillator

January 2014

Awarded 'Best Mobile Application' at DevLearn 2014 for the Virtual Zoll Defibrillator app, an iPad trainer that teaches everyone how to use an automated defibrillation device in the event of a cardiac arrest.

GROUPS

IGDA

2009 to Present

International Game Developer's Association - idga.org

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

TECHNOLOGIES:

- Unity3D Game Engine
- AutoDesk Maya C#
- Unreal4 Engine
- Articulate Storyline 2 Flash, Actionscript
- Adobe Creative Cloud
- Oculus SDK SteamVR